# Viktor Vidolov

Junior Developer

# PERSONAL PROFILE

An aspiring developer, I am proactive and always ready to learn. I enjoy experimenting with new languages or systems and I have a broad understanding of the essentials, giving me the opportunity to adapt quickly to new challenges. My professional experience of 6 years in various roles in tech companies combined with my mathematics background allow me to work with a diverse skill set.

# **CONTACT DETAILS**

vidolarez@gmail.com
+44 7591 033145
+359 88 903 0199

Sofia, Bulgaria

√viktorvidolov

viktorvidolov.com

# PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

# TECHNICAL SUPPORT SERVICE

Bose Corporation - Chatham, Kent

November 2018 - Present

Providing 3rd level support for smart speakers and LAN troubleshooting. Developing internal knowledge base for the service centre using MS SharePoint. Developing automation for day to day tasks with MS Workflow.

# MULTI SUPPLIER ORGANISATION COORDINATOR

DXC Technology - Sofia, Bulgaria
September 2016 - September 2018
Organized technical teams and prepared
Disaster Recovery Plans for applications
and services. Took up additional
responsibilities like Change Management,
Technical training for our team and
SharePoint development.

# CONTINUITY PROGRAM MANAGER

Hewlett Packard Enterprise - Sofia, Bulgaria

August 2015 - September 2015

Responsible for keeping the SLA for business continuity arrangement between HPE and E.On. Spoke tight communication with the technical teams associated with the provided infrastructure. Regularly held meetings and prepared monthly reports for both internal and external needs.

# TECHNICAL ADVISOR

Freelance - Sofia, Bulgaria

September 2014 - May 2015

Worked as both tech support and a secretary for a paediatrician's office. Kept technology in working order and took office duties. I have had no unsolved technical problems for 9 months and have automated 50% of the previously manual labour.

#### TEACHER - DIGITAL SOUND RECORDING

Sofia, Bulgaria

September 2012 - September 2014

Taught young perspective students recording and editing skills for digital audio. I was the first alumni to become a teacher at our school studio.

Successfully trained one of my pupils and they are currently working in the largest radio group in Sofia.

# **EDUCATION**

# **SOFTWARE ENGINEERING**

SoftUni

Remote - In progress

An online university founded by some of my colleagues in from when I studied applied mathematics. I have grown to love the system and I have managed to catch up quickly with my programming skills. It has been a new passion to learn new languages and solidify old ones.

# TECHNICAL SKILLS

Intermediate C#
Basic C++
HTML/CSS
Basic Python
JIRA
Adobe Photoshop
Adobe Premiere PRO
Adobe AfterEffects

# SOFT SKILLS

Perseverance
Resolution seeking
Time Management
Program Management
Continuity Management

# **LANGUAGES**

Bulgarian (Native) English (Proficient) Hebrew (Intermediate)

# **CERTIFICATES**

ITIL Foundation Certificate in IT Service Management 2016-Present Certificate number 5883531.20613735

# MINI-DEGREE, COMPUTER GAMES AND PROGRAMMING SKILLS

Zenva Academy

2017-2019

Started learning basic Unity and C# usage to get acquainted with game development and design. I have started developing a couple of short games.

# APPLIED MATHEMATICS

Sofia University St. Kliment Ohridski

October 2014 - Not Graduated

Studied mathematics because of my passion for game design, but after a while, I learned to love developing and learning new coding languages. I plan on continuing my studies on a part time basis in the future.

# ADDITIONAL PROJECTS

#### KIOSK SYSTEM DEPLOYMENT

2020

Deployed a system with an android application for "Best Cars". The purpose of the project was to create a kiosk system for partnering hotels to ease the access to potential customers. Managed to plan, program and deliver the whole service for 3 days, mostly using a scaling website to translate as an application.

#### **RAINWAY**

2020

Translated Rainway to my native language. It is a streaming solution for local private gaming servers. Started my ongoing practice with GitHub.